PHILIP BROWNE

 • Washington DC/Baltimore | ☐ (443) 459-7382 | ☑ pbrowne@gmail.com | ♠ PhilipBrowne | Im PhilipBrowneTech | ∰ www.philiprowne.com

Full Stack Software Engineer with a passion for helping people through technology and finding ways to efficiently and collaboratively solve problems. Dedicated and detail-oriented professional with a background of more than a decade as an orchestral musician and a proven record of success in multiple industries.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Go/Golang

Libraries/Frameworks/Protocols: Bootstrap, jQuery, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Flask, REST, GraphQL, Protocol Buffers,

gRPC, Selenium

Databases: SQL (PostgreSQL, SQLite, MySQL), MongoDB, ElasticSearch, Neo4j, DynamoDB

Testing: Jasmine, Jest, React Test Library, PyTest

CI/CD & Deployment: Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, Azure, Google Cloud Platform, Jenkins, GitHub, GitLab

PROJECTS

Voter Info / Repository Link

2021

Full-Stack Voter Information Application using Google Civic Information, EasyPost, and MapQuest APIs

Technologies Used: JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, AJAX, Axios, Python, Flask, Bcrypt, SQLAlchemy, PostgreSQL

Space Force / Repository Link

2021

- Full-Stack Platform Game developed for Mintbean.io Hiring Hackathon built with PhaserJS Library. Mintbean Star Award Winner for "exemplary achievement in the field of web development"
- Technologies Used: JavaScript, PhaserJS, JavaScript State Machine, Bootstrap, Python, Flask, Bcrypt, SQLAlchemy PostgreSQL

WORK EXPERIENCE

Backend Software Engineer

2022 - Present

Megaport

- Develop back-end services using modern development practices and technology stacks including Go and gRPC.
- Work closely with Product Teams and UX designers to create APIs consumable by Front-End Developers.
- Manage Cloud Native software deployments to multiple cloud providers including Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud, and Microsoft Azure.

Full Stack Developer

2021

M-Partners Incorporated

- Developed and maintained both independent and collaborative projects for small startup specializing in new concepts in data analytics, artificial intelligence, and machine learning to enable automatic end-to-end data collection, processing, and analysis.
- Built scalable and highly reliable products and maintained uptime of existing applications.

Freelance Musician

2009 - Present

• Professional Orchestral French Horn player with experience working with groups such as the Baltimore Symphony, Virginia Symphony, Richmond Symphony, Pittsburgh Opera, and National Philharmonic, among others.

EDUCATION

Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Maryland

Graduated with BM in 2009, GPD in 2012

Bachelor of Music, French Horn Performance; Graduate Performance Diploma (GPD), French Horn Performance

Yale University Graduate School of Music

2012-2014

Springboard Software Engineering Career Track Fellowship

2021

An 800-hour fellowship that covers key aspects of front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms. Modules include learning resources, practice exercises, projects, and career-related coursework.